<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Notes on Web Development</title><link>https://phhtnn.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Notes on Web Development</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://phhtnn.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hugo Setup for GitHub Pages</title><link>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/12/29/hugo-setup-for-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/12/29/hugo-setup-for-github-pages/</guid><description>Just to note that Hugo&amp;rsquo;s guide on how to host the site on GitHub Pages is a great help. The work on building and deploying is mostly done by the GitHub Actions for GitHub Pages and Hugo. There is also advice on the first deployment. Also, I&amp;rsquo;d like to note that using a public repository for the site meant that I had to pay attention to the license.</description></item><item><title>Updating Libraries with npm</title><link>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/12/07/updating-libraries-with-npm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/12/07/updating-libraries-with-npm/</guid><description>A short note on updating libraries with Node.js and npm. One gets the audit report with the command npm audit. The command npm audit fix could be used to fix the vulnerabilities. If a fix is not available, there are suggested steps one can take.
One thing I learned from updating a project with a rather dated package.json was that there might not be a need to make (all) the major version update(s) to get a fix to the reported vulnerability.</description></item><item><title>Validating Forms (with React)</title><link>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/12/02/validating-forms-with-react/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/12/02/validating-forms-with-react/</guid><description>I think that trying to build form validations from scratch helped me learn a lot about web development. I&amp;rsquo;d do many things differently now, but here&amp;rsquo;s a couple things I learned during the process. First, I think that I understand the different roles of frontend, backend and database dependant validation much better than a couple of months ago. Second, at this point I&amp;rsquo;m pretty much agreeing with the idea that in most cases, the form state in React is best managed locally rather than globally with e.</description></item><item><title>Workflow with Git</title><link>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/12/01/workflow-with-git/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/12/01/workflow-with-git/</guid><description>I think that working with a team on a common source code helped to improve my skills in version control. It seems to me that there are things one can learn using Git on a project of one&amp;rsquo;s own. And then there are workflows that one develops while collaborating with others. These four groups of Git users described in the Git documentation make a lot sense now. I&amp;rsquo;m hope that I moved a bit closer to the level of &amp;ldquo;Individual Developer (Participant)&amp;rdquo; during this autumn.</description></item><item><title>VS Code Tips</title><link>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/11/29/vs-code-tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/11/29/vs-code-tips/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve got two tips (to myself) on using VS Code to be more productive in software development.
First, one occasionally needs some data e.g. in an array to help reason about logic of the code. A copy-and-paste operation into a JavaScript file could be all that is needed. However, one might still want to do some styling of the data. This Stack Overflow post gives the details on how to use the multi-cursor feature to help with a task like breaking the data into rows.</description></item><item><title>Mounts in Docker</title><link>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/11/24/mounts-in-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/11/24/mounts-in-docker/</guid><description>A quick note on mounts in Docker just to collect some useful links and hopefully reinforce some learning as there isn&amp;rsquo;t much point in repeating the Docker documentation here. The basics of named volumes and bind mounts are covered in the Get started guide. The more detailed information on managing data is also very helpful in choosing, which kind of mount to use in different use cases. Also, links to more detailed information on volumes, bind mounts and tmpfs mounts is provided.</description></item><item><title>Hugo CI/CD Pipeline in GitLab</title><link>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/11/23/hugo-pipeline-in-gitlab/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://phhtnn.github.io/note/2021/11/23/hugo-pipeline-in-gitlab/</guid><description>A Static Site Generator called Hugo and the XMin theme are used to build these pages. GitLab&amp;rsquo;s Hugo template for GitLab Pages helped a lot getting started. There were a couple of things to sort out to get everything running smoothly on LabraNet&amp;rsquo;s GitLab.
First, the project should be named ab1234.pages.labranet.jamk.fi, where ab1234 is the username, to get the defaults working for user pages. Second, Labranet&amp;rsquo;s GitLab Runner has a tag associated with it and it needs to be added to the file .</description></item></channel></rss>